irspace.com 2019-03-24

# Privacy Policy

**IRspace Privacy Notice**

**1\. Purpose of this Notice**

**This privacy notice explains our approach to any personal information that you might supply to us (or that might be collected from you) in connection with your use of IRspace and set out your rights in respect of our processing of your personal information**.

We respect the privacy of every person who visits, registers with or subscribes to any of our websites and online publications (including IRspace), and are committed to ensuring a safe online experience.

This privacy notice explains our approach to any personal information that you might supply to us (or that might be collected from you) in connection with your use of IRspace.

This privacy notice also explains your rights in respect of our processing of your personal information.  In particular, this privacy notice will inform you how you can verify the accuracy of your personal information that is collected by us through IRspace and how you can request that we delete, update or transfer it.

This privacy notice is intended to assist you in making informed decisions when using IRspace. Please take a moment to read and understand it. Please note that it should be read in conjunction with our [Terms of Use.](http://www.irspace.com/pages/terms-and-conditions)

Please also note that this privacy notice only applies to the use of personal information collected by us from your use of IRspace or during your communications with us. It does not apply to your communications with any other third party.

**2\. Who are we and what do we do?**

IRspace is operated by IR Media Group Limited (“ **IR Media** ”).  IR Media is the data controller responsible for your personal information.   IR Media is registered at the UK Information Commissioner’s Office with registration number: Z2550846

IR Media is an English company with registered company number: 03724289 whose principal address is The Office Group Building, 133 Whitechapel High Street, London, E1 7QA, United Kingdom.

IR Media’s principal business activities include:

  * Business-to-business publishing
  * Events, including conferences and awards
  * Market research

IR Media is the owner of the IR Magazine and Corporate Secretary brands and has one wholly-owned subsidiary, IR Media Group (USA) Inc, based in New York, USA.

**3\. How to contact us?**

If you have any questions about this privacy notice or want to exercise your rights, please contact us by:

  * sending an email to [support@irspace.com](mailto:support@irspace.com);
  * calling us on +44 20 8004 5340; or
  * writing to us at IR Media Group Limited, The Office Group Building, 133 Whitechapel High Street, London, E1 7QA, UK, marking your letter for the attention of the Data Protection Officer.

**4\. What personal information we collect?**

Our primary goal in collecting personal information from you is to give you an enjoyable customized experience while allowing us to provide services and features that most likely meet your needs.

We collect certain personal information from you, which you give to us when signing up to and using IRspace.

When you initially sign up and create an account we require the following personal information from you:

  * Name
  * Email address
  * Job title
  * Company name
  * Password

When you fill out your profile we may collect the following additional personal information from you:

  * Work history
  * Education history
  * IR Association membership (if relevant)
  * Qualifications
  * Professional accreditations
  * Skills

When completing your profile you can provide as much or as little detail as you see fit.  However, the more detail you provide, the more you will get out of IRspace. 

**Please be aware that any personal information you choose to share on IRspace (including your profile details) will be made publically available to other members of IRspace, unless you choose to make your email address invisible. Therefore please think carefully before sharing such personal information.  ** **For more information on your privacy settings please view[your profile settings](http://www.irspace.com/settings-privacy). **

If you contact us, we may collect other contact details from you such as a telephone number.

We may also collect certain personal information regarding your use of and activity on IRspace (for example, what connections you have made, which forums you have participated in etc).

Further we may collection personal information regarding your mobile device, computer hardware and software used to access IRspace.  This may include the following:

  * IP address of device(s) used;
  * browser type;
  * operating system and device type;
  * approximate location (e.g. London or Tokyo);
  * access times and dates; and
  * referring website addresses.

**5\. How do we collect personal information?**

**We may collect personal information voluntarily provided by you (e.g. when registering or creating a profile).We may also collect personal information through use of cookies to** **allow us to deliver a better service to you.   Please see [Use of cookies](http://www.irspace.com/pages/cookies) ****for further information.**

When you visit and use IRspace you may provide us with, or we may collect, your personal information in a number of ways:

**_Information you voluntarily provide to us_**

We collect and maintain personal information that you voluntarily submit to us during your use of the IRspace (e.g. when registering or creating a profile, during the course of email exchanges with us or other members, as part of any customer support interactions and/or surveys, or when participating in discussions and/or forums ).

**_Information we collect through your use of IRspace_**

As you use IRspace, personal information may also be passively collected by us through our use of cookies, pixels, beacons, log files and other technologies. This Personal information allows us to deliver more helpful information, services and tools. Please see [**Use of cookies**](http://www.irspace.com/pages/cookies) for further information.

**_Information we collect from our other IR Media sites_**

We may also combine personal information received from your use of our other IR Media sites ([www.irmagazine.com](http://www.irmagazine.com/) or [www.corporatesecretary.com](http://www.corporatesecretary.com/)) with your personal information submitted to IRspace.

We do not collect personal information about our site visitors or online registered users or subscribers from other sources, such as public records or bodies, or private organisations.

**6\. How we use your personal information?**

We collect and use your personal information to operate IRspace efficiently and to deliver the products and services you have requested.

In particular, your personal information may be used for the purposes of:

**Purpose**

| 

**Detail**

| 

**Legal Basis**  
  
---|---|---  
  
**Service administration and compliance**

| 

We may use your personal information to

  * ensure that the content on IRspace is presented in the most relevant and effective manner for you and your device;
  * enable you to use the interactive features of the IRspace;
  * provide services that you have requested;
  * check that you comply with the Terms of Use;
  * develop and improve IRspace;
  * administrative emails about IRspace; and
  * contact you to answer any queries you may have.

| 

It’s in our legitimate interest to use your personal information in such a way to monitor compliance and ensure that we provide the very best service we can to you.  
  
**User Data Analysis**

| 

We may use your personal information on an anonymised basis to analyse, benchmark and conduct research on user data and user interactions with IRspace.

| 

It’s in our legitimate interest to continually evaluate personal information to ensure we are aware of market trends and ensure that the content on IRspace  and the service we provide is relevant to you.  
  
**Internal Record Keeping**

| 

We may use your personal information for internal record keeping purposes

| 

It’s in our legitimate interest to ensure that we keep our records up to date in order to monitor who uses our service and to comply with our legal and regulatory obligations.  
  
**Monitoring Content**

| 

Where we enable you to post information or materials on IRspace, we may access and monitor any personal information which you upload or input, including in any password-protected sections, in order to fulfil our obligations to you, monitor your compliance  and protect or comply with our legal rights and obligations.

| 

It’s in our legitimate interest to monitor the users of IRspace to ensure we can fulfil our obligations to them, monitor their compliance and protect or comply with their legal rights and obligations.  
  
**Downloading**

| 

Where you download from IRspace (in accordance with our Terms of Use)  information,  articles or other content made available by third party providers, your name and email address and such other information notified to you at time of download may be passed on to those third party providers. Each time you download, you will be notified of what personal information will be shared and the third party with which it will be shared. 

| 

It’s in our legitimate interest to comply with requests of third parties who publish content on IRspace for details of users who are downloading such content.  
  
**Marketing**

| 

Unless you tell us you don’t want to receive them, we may use your personal information to contact you by email, telephone and/or post for sending information or promotional material on the products and/or services of IR Media.

| 

It’s in our legitimate interest to market our business.  You can choose not to be contacted in this way, when you register with us, and at any time afterwards.  
  
**Sharing information with group companies and other affiliated and associated entities**

| 

Subject to your consent we may share your personal information with other group companies and other entities affiliated or associated with IRspace including Bank of America Merrill Lynch, founding sponsors of IRspace.

| 

Your consent  
  
**Sharing information with other third parties**

| 

We may share your personal information with other third parties (including professional advisers, or governmental or state institutions or authorities):

  * to enable them to process your personal information on our behalf in a manner consistent with this privacy notice;
  * to comply with our legal obligations;
  * to enforce our legal rights; or
  * protect rights of third parties.

Your personal information and any Content you upload to IRspace may also be shared with prospective buyers if we go through a business transition such as a merger, acquisition by another company, or sale of all or a portion of our assets.

| 

It’s in our legitimate interest to share personal information with such third parties to enable them to process your information on our behalf, to comply with and/or enforce our legal rights and obligations, to protect the rights of third parties and to facilitate business transitions.  
  
Any other purposes for which we wish to use your personal information will be notified to you and your personal information will not be used for any such purpose without obtaining your prior consent.

**7\. How to provide us with consent?**

Where use of your personal information by us requires your consent, you can provide such consent:

  * at time of collection following the instructions provided; or
  * by informing IR Media by email, post or phone using the contact details set out in this privacy statement.

**8\. Children**

**You are required to be at least 18 years old to use IRspace so we do not intentionally collect personal information from anyone under 18, and no one under 18 should attempt to submit any personal information to IRspace.** **Should we discover that any such personal information has been delivered to any of the sites, we will remove that personal information as soon as possible.**

**9\. Use of cookies**

**IRspace uses certain cookies of which you should be aware.**

All IR Media’s sites (including IRspace) use 'cookies'.

A cookie is a text file placed on your hard drive by a web page server. Cookies cannot be used to run programs or deliver viruses to your computer. They are uniquely assigned to you and can only be read by a web server in the domain that issued the cookie.

Cookies are either used only during your session ('temporary' or 'session state' cookies) or stored on your computer's hard drive ('permanent' cookies).

Temporary cookies are a mechanism for maintaining continuity between pages during your visit. These cookies are maintained in your browser’s active memory and are terminated at the conclusion of the site visit. Permanent cookies are used to recall on subsequent visits your login information and your agreement to our terms and conditions.

Some of the cookies we use are integral to the functioning of all IRspace.

By using your browser’s options to block all cookies you may prohibit effective use of IRspace. For example, cookies are used to keep you logged in as you navigate between pages on our website, to set your language preferences, and to ensure that online payment facilities function properly. If you still wish to control the operation of cookies, then functionality is available through your browser. Generally you have the options to accept all cookies, to be notified when a cookie is issued or reject all cookies. 

[Click here to find out more about the cookies we use and how to manage and delete cookies](http://www.irmagazine.com/cookies/)[.](http://www.irspace.com/pages/cookies)

As outlined above, disabling all cookies may prevent IRspace from operating fully.

**10\. Third Party Links and Services**

IRspace contains links to third party websites. Please remember that when you use a link to go from IRspace to another website or you request a service from a third party, this privacy notice no longer applies.

Your browsing and interaction on any other website, or your dealings with any other third party service provider, is subject to that website’s or third party service provider’s own rules and policies. 

We do not monitor, control, or endorse the personal information collection or privacy practices of any third parties.

We encourage you to become familiar with the privacy practices of every website you visit or third party service provider that you deal with and to contact them if you have any questions about their respective privacy policies and practices.

This privacy statement applies solely to personal information collected by us through IRspace or our services and does not apply to these third party websites and third party service providers.

IRspace may also contain advertisements for, and/or the opportunity for you to purchase products or services from third parties. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this personal information used by these companies, click here: <http://www.advertising.com/Privacy.html>

**11\. Transfers outside the EEA**

**We  may transfer your personal information, for the purposes listed above, to other group companies or other third parties that may be located in countries outside the European Economic Area, whose laws are not recognized by the EU Commission as providing adequate level of protection to personal information**.

**12\. How long do we keep your personal information for?**

We keep your personal information only for as long as necessary to fulfil the purpose it was collected for.

**13\. Confidentiality and security of your personal information**

We are committed to keeping the personal information you provide us secure and will take reasonable precautions to protect your personal information from loss, misuse or alteration.

We have implemented information security policies, rules and technical measures to protect the personal information that we have under our control from:

  * unauthorised access
  * improper use or disclosure
  * unauthorised modification
  * unlawful destruction or accidental loss.

All our employees and data processors (i.e. those who process your personal information on our behalf, for the purposes listed above), who have access to, and are associated with the processing of personal information, are obliged to respect the confidentiality of our site visitors' personal information.

**14\. How to access your information and you other rights?**

**You have a number of rights in relation to the personal information we hold about you.   For example you have the right to access your personal information, rectify your personal information, erase your personal information, restrict our processing of your personal information, object to certain types of processing of your personal information, require us to transfer a copy of your personal information to you or a third party and/or lodge complaint.  If you want to exercise any of these rights, please contact us at [support@irspace.com](mailto:support@irspace.com).**

We set out below your rights with respect of the personal information we hold about you: 

**The right of access**

| 

If you ask us, we’ll confirm whether we’re processing your personal information and, if so, provide you with a copy of that personal information (along with certain other details). In some circumstances, we may need to charge a reasonable fee.  
  
---|---  
  
**The right to rectification**

| 

If the personal information we have about you is inaccurate or incomplete, you’re entitled to have it rectified. If we’ve shared your personal information with others, we’ll let them know about the rectification where possible. If you ask us, we’ll also tell you who we’ve shared your personal information with.  
  
**The right to erasure**

| 

You can ask us to delete or remove your personal information in some circumstances such as where we no longer need it or you withdraw your consent (where applicable). If we’ve shared your personal information with others, we’ll let them know about the erasure where possible. If you ask us, where possible we’ll also tell you who we’ve shared your personal information with.

Note: This may be very complicated to track every interaction on a network, would like to caveat this as where possible, reasonable means etc. OK to leave if legally required.  
  
**The right to restrict processing**

| 

You can ask us to ‘block’ or suppress the processing of your personal information in certain circumstances such as where you contest the accuracy of that personal information or object to us processing it. It won’t stop us from storing your personal information though. We’ll tell you before we lift any restriction. If we’ve shared your personal information with others, we’ll let them know about the restriction where possible. If you ask us, we’ll also tell you who we’ve shared your personal information with.  
  
**The right to data portability**

| 

You have the right, in certain circumstances, to obtain personal information you’ve provided us with (in a structured, commonly used and machine readable format) and to reuse it elsewhere.  
  
**The right to object**

| 

You can ask us to stop processing your personal information if we’re:

  * relying on our own or someone else’s legitimate interests to process your personal information;
  * processing your personal information for direct marketing; or
  * processing your personal information for research.

**Rights in relation to automated decision making and profiling**

| 

You have the right not to be subject to a decision when it’s based on automatic processing, including profiling, and it produces a legal effect or similarly significantly affects you.  
  
**The right to withdraw consent**

| 

If we rely on your consent (or explicit consent) as our legal basis for processing your personal information, you have the right to withdraw that consent at any time.  
  
**The right to lodge a complaint with the supervisory authority**

| 

If you have a concern about any aspect of our personal information rights practices, including the way we’ve handled your personal information, you can report it to the UK Information Commissioner’s Office (ICO). You can find details about how to do this on the ICO website at <https://ico.org.uk/concerns/> or by calling their helpline on 0303 123 1113.  
  
Please note that in order to exercise your rights, you be required to follow our identification procedures so that we are sure you are who you say you are!

**15\. Changes to this privacy notice**

**We may make changes to this privacy notice from time to time.**

To ensure that you are always aware of how we use your personal information we will update this privacy notice from time to time to reflect any changes to our use of your personal information.  We may also make changes as required to comply with changes in applicable law or regulatory requirements.  We encourage you to review this privacy notice periodically to be informed of how IR Media uses your personal information.

Last Updated [January 2017]
